Register of the Herbert Hoover subject collection, 1895-2006
Hoover Institution Archives
- PHONOTAPES, 1931-1964
  - Interview with Hoover by Allan Nevins and Frank Ernest Hill, 1950. (Reel 11)
    This copy is the Third Duplicate, made December, 1966
    (end label)
    Hoover describes his work in the Department of Commerce on the regulation of radio.
    Use copy reference number: 62008_a_0008747
  - "Our National Policies in This Crisis," New York., December 20, 1951 (Reel 12)
    Hoover speaks about the problems facing the United States, but with an emphasis on foreign relations and martial matters.
    Use copy reference number: 62008_a_0008745
  - "The Constructive Character of the Republican Party," New York., October 18, 1952 (Reel 13-14)
    Former president Hoover speaks to 40 million of the electorate that came of age since he was in office. He advocates the election of Eisenhower and the Republican Party. In the process, attempting to debunk commonly held beliefs, he examines actions of the Republican Party in the first third of the 20th century, the New Deal, reactionary politics, conservation of natural resources, corruption, and isolationism.
    This address is a compliment to a press release sent out by the Republican National Committee.
    Use copy reference number: 62008_a_0008744
  - Herbert Hoover's 75th Birthday, Stanford., 1953 (Reel 15)
  - "Farm City Conference Economy Award," New York., May 25, 1954 (Reel 16)
  - "On the Reorganization of the Federal Government, Washington, D.C., January 29, 1955 (Reel 17-20)
  - "Our American Way of Life," Newberg, Oregon., August 11, 1955 (Reel 21)
    Use copy reference number: 62008_a_0008746
    Herbert Hoover speaks at a childhood home in Newberg, Oregon, as part of a dedication ceremony.
  - "Address Before the Centennial Convention of the Republican Party," San Francisco., August 21, 1956 (Reel 22)
  - Address, Women's National Republican Club., March 9, 1957 (Reel 23)
  - Address, Boy of the Year Award., March 10, 1957 (Reel 24)
  - "The Strengths of America," Grocery Manufacturers of America, New York., November 11, 1957 (Reel 25)
  - "It's Your Business, No. 50," Interview of Hoover by Paul Manning., December 15, 1957. (Reel 26)
  - "Message to the Belgian People,", June 25, 1958. (Reel 27)
  - "On American Ideals," Belgian World's Fair., July 4, 1958. (Reel 28)
  - "Some Observations on Current American Life," National Council of United Presbyterian Men, New York., February 13, 1960 (Reel 29)
  - Interview of Herbert Hoover by Ken Colgrove and Frank Mason, June 29, 1961. (Reel 30-31)
    Use copy reference number: 62008_a_0010317
  - Address, Dedication of the Engineering Building of the Cooper Union for the Advancement of Science and Art., September 15, 1961. (Reel 32)
  - "Proposal for Greater Safety for America: The Assurance That We Are Not In the Decline and Fall of the American Way of Life." Dedication of the Herbert Hoover Presidential Library, West Branch, Iowa., August 10, 1962. (Reel 33)
  - Herbert Hoover Memorial, NBC., October 20, 1964 (Reel 34)
    Use copy reference number: 62008_a_0008748
  - Herbert Hoover Obituary, NBC., October 20, 1964 (Reel 35-36)
    Use copy reference number: 62008_a_0008749
- PHOTOGRAPHS
  3,334 photographs of Herbert Hoover as a boy and at various stages in his career, as well as photographs of the Hoover family circle and their homes.
  - 3 negatives: 1 of Hoover Dam; 1 of Hoover Dike (Mississippi River), and 1 of memorial plate (Hoover Dike)., undated (Folder A, mXXX)
  - 21 photos of H. Hoover's ancestors., undated (Folder B)
  - 23 photos, 1 neg., pertaining to H. Hoover's childhood and youth., undated (Folder C)
  - 11 photos of H. Hoover as a Stanford student., undated (Folder D)
  - 26 photos, 3 neg., of H. Hoover as a young man., undated (Folder E)
  - 37 photos, 1 neg., of Mr and Mrs. Hoover and their family., undated (Folder F)
  - 58 photos of Mr. and Mrs. Hoover with or of their dogs., undated (Folder G, mWWW, m*)
  - 57 photos of H. Hoover's visit to Finland., 1938 (Folder H)
  - 119 photos pertaining to the Finnish Relief Fund, Inc., 1940 (Folder I)
  - 6 photos of H. Hoover at Stanford, Hoover Tower (in his office)., undated (Folder J)
  - 5 photos pertaining to the Polish Relief Fund, Inc., 1940 (Folder K)
  - 31 photos, 1 neg., of H. Hoover as Food Administrator, 1917-1918; 1 glass slide of Woodrow Wilson. 1 album with 65 photos of publicity posters. (Folder L, mYYY, m*, f)
  - 15 photos, 1 neg., of H. Hoover as Chairman of the Commission for Relief in Belgium (CRB), 1914 ff.; included is a photo of King Alber and Queen Elizabeth. (Folder m, mZZZ)
  - 121 photos pertaining to the C.R.B (people, ship loading, barges, warehouses, statistics, etc.), undated (Folder N-O, m*, mIIII)
  - 60 photos, 1 neg., of H. Hoover on various fishing trips to Nevada, Wyoming, Oregon, Florida, and the President's Camp at the Rapidan River., 1920-52 (Folder P)
  - 89 photos of the President's Camp at the Rapidan (interior and exterior) depicting Mr. and Mrs. Hoover and visitors., undated (Folder R-T)
  - 80 photos, 1 neg., 1 map, showing H. Hoover as Secretary of Commerce, also Mrs. Hoover, Presidents Harding and Coolidge, and cabinet members., 1921-28 (Folder U-V, mAAAA)
  - 38 photos of offices used during Mr. Hoover's term as Secretary of Commerce., undated (Folder W)
  - 33 photos of the Hoovers' house, 623 Mirada Rd., Stanford, built from 1920-23, (exterior and interior)., undated (Folder X)
  - 22 photos of H. Hoover's birthplace in West Branch, Iowa, including photos of the cottage, the blacksmith shop, the library, and of Mr. Hoover, family members, and friends., Aug. 1948 (Folder Y)
  - 3 photos: 1 of H. Hoover (A.R.A) period); 1 of Col. A.C. Goodyear (A.R.A official); and 1 of an Industrial Conference meeting, appointed by Pres. Wilson in Dec. 1919. (Folder Z)
  - 39 photos, 5 neg., of H. Hoover at the Bohemian Grove, California, and at the Bohemian Club in San Francisco., undated (Folder AA)
  - 14 photos, 1 neg., pertaining to King Albert and Queen Elizabeth of Belgium's visit to San Francisco., 1919 (Folder BB)
  - 14 photos of the White House interior which were used by Mrs. Dare Stark McMullin as illustrations in her "Heirlooms; and anthology of White House Furniture", undated (Folder CC, mBBBB)
  - 40 photos pertaining to Lou Henry Hoover, Herbert Hoover and their respective families., undated (Folder DD, mCCCC, m*)
  - 76 photos of Mr. and Mrs. Hoover, Mark Sullivan and others on their South American cruise on the USS Maryland., 1929 (Folder EE-FF)
  - 39 photos of H. Hoover's cruise to Puerto Rico and the Virgin Islands., March 19-30, 1931 (Folder GG)
  - 42 photos of Pres. Hoover and his cabinet members and/or their wives playing medicine ball., undated (Folder HH)
  - 1 neg. of a letter from the Supreme Economic Council, Office of the Director Gen. of Relief, signed by H. Hoover to Prof. E.D. Adams re: a $50,000 fund for Stanford University Library (Hoover?)., June 20, 1929 (Folder II)
  - 291 photos, 1 neg., 2 clipp., pertaining to H. Hoover's campaign trips, his acceptance speech, etc., undated (Folder JJ-MM, mDDDD)
  - 33 photos, 65 neg., of H. Hoover awards., undated (Folder NN)
  - 38 photos, 1 clip., of H. Hoover as President-elect., undated (Folder OO, mEEEE)
  - 298 photos, 2 neg., 17 clipp., 3 mounted clippings, pertaining to H. Hoover (presidential period) 106 of these prints were taken by the N.Y. Times photographer (1929-1933), also 3 engravings., undated (Folder PP-TT, mFFFF, m*)
  - 20 photos, 24 neg., itinerary, of the 1932 campaign trip, including pictures of H. Hoover and photos of southwestern scenery and a parade in San Francisco. (Folder VV)
  - 98 miscellaneous photos, 4 neg., 2 clip., undated (Folder ww,m*)
  - 20 photos pertaining to the A.R.A and the A.R.A E.C.F. periods., undated (Folder xx, mGGGG, m*)
  - 66 photos pertaining to the A.R.A. in Russia and in the Baltics., undated (Folder YY)
  - 26 photos pertaining to A.R.A activities in Vienna, Austria (kitchens, etc.); 1 painting., undated (Folder ZZ)
  - 2 photos: 1 re: the Gold Medal Award (Stanford Alumni Association, March 5, 1963). 1 re: the "Honorary Past Commander-in-Chief (in perpetuity of the Military Order to the World Wars" (Citation), 1966. (Folder AAA)
  - 17 photos of H. Hoover's apartment at the Walderf Astoria in New York City., undated (Folder BBB)
  - 9 photos of H. Hoover and others on Veterans Day at Arlington National Cemetery., Nov. 11, 1955 (Folder CCC)
  - 2 photos of the "Red House," Kensington London, one-time home of the Hoovers, taken by Mrs. Barbara Hall, London, the day before the last act of demolition., March 1972 (Folder DDD)
  - 1 photo of Jane Addams, Pres. of Women's International League for Peace., undated (Folder EEE)
  - 145 photos, 1 neg., pertaining to H. Hoover's funeral and burial services and sites in Wash., D.C., New York, and West Branch, Iowa. (14 in colour)., undated (Folder FFF-HHH)
  - 1 photo of Grace Coolidge, wife of the 30th President of the United States., undated (Folder mIII)
  - 2 filmstrips of pages 1-102 of a Herbert Hoover photo album (?)., undated (Folder JJJ)
  - 221 photos, 4 neg., 3 clipp., of H. Hoover and others pertaining to the post-presidential period. (Many pictures taken at the Bohemian Grove)., undated (Folder UU, KKK-NNN, mHHHH, m*)
  - 21 miscellaneous photos, 9 neg., (Alaska, Stanford tracks)., undated (Folder OOO)
  - 26 photos (in 1 album) of H. Hoover and others taken during his visit to Rhode-St. Genese? Belgium., July 5, 1958 (Folder PPP)
  - 560 photos pertaining to the Famine Emergency Committee., 1946-1947 (Folder QQQ-TTT)
  - 163 photos of Lawrence Richey (one of H. Hoover's secretaries and friends. (Folder UUU-VVV, mKKKK)
  - 1 photo (negative) of a flour sack of the G.J. Burrer Milling Co. of Sunbury, Ohio, which is on display in the Herbert Hoover Room, Hoover Tower., undated (Folder WWW)
  - 22 prints of televised coverage of Herbert Hoover's appearance at the Republican national Convention, San Francisco., 1956 (Folder XXX)
  - 8 prints of President and Mrs. Herbert Hoover, February-March 1933, and of the counting of electoral ballots for President and Vice President, February 1933 (Folder YYY)
  - 1 print and 1 negative of President Hoover and Miss Bane with a Peruvian Paracas Mantle, October 3, 1956 (Folder ZZZ)
  - 9 miscellaneous prints: 4 prints of Washington, D.C.; 1 print of a portrait of Herbert Hoover; 1 page of a photograph album; 2 prints of Herbert Hoover with others., undated (Folder mLLLL)
  - 1 framed drawing of Herbert Hoover with handwritten inscription to Nina Almond from Herbert Hoover., undated (Folder mMMMM)
  - 12 prints related to American relief in Poland including prints of Herbert Hoover in Poland in 1919 and 1946; 1 print of Herbert Hoover speaking in behalf of the Polish Relief Fund, 1939; 1 print of memorial to Herbert Hoover in Warsaw, Poland. 3 negatives: 1 of Herbert Hoover with Polish Children, 1946; 1 of a map of Poland showing principal warehouses and cities where American Relief Administration carried on relief for children programs; 1 of a graph showing the number of children and mothers fed by the American Relief Administration, 1919-1921. (Folder AAAA)
  - 3 negative photographs: 1 of the California Republican Assembly Award, at the Republican National Convention, San Francisco, California, 1956. Original award is at the Herbert Hoover Presidential Library, West Branch, Iowa; 2 of Herbert C. Hoover's diploma from Stanford University, 1895 original diploma is at the Hoover Institution on War, Revolution and Peace, Stanford., undated (Folder BBBB)
  - 7 photos, 1920-1928, 3 photos, South American Trip, Nov. 28- Jan. 29., 4 photos, 1929., 7 photos, 1930., 5 photos, 1931., 18 photos, 1932. 1 photo, 1938, 5 photos, presidential period. (Folder m*NNNN)
  - 4 photos presidential era., undated (Folder mOOOO)
  - 1 framed photo portrait of Hoover Commerce period., undated (Folder CCCC)
  - 1 framed print of sketch of Herbert Hoover by Clareuce Mattei., 1933 (Folder Art rack 20, back)